How do holograms work? If I said magic,
would you believe me?
Okay, fine. Holography is the practice
of recording an interference pattern
using coherent light um within a
holographic substrate. Well, what does
that mean? Number one, interference
pattern. Think of the light waves like
water waves, right? Waves be waving.
Simple example. I throw two rocks into
the water and what happens? We get
ripples. Whoa. Those are waves, right?
All right. So this thing you're looking
at here with the ripple ripples this is
a wavefront. Okay. Now all these little
points in which the waves are
intersecting basically these coherent
light waves are intersecting. It's
little tiny little points those are
interference points. And you might be
thinking Travis what do these two rocks
have to do with anything? It's just a
good starting point. So now we
understand wave interference right uh on
a two-dimensional aquatic plane. Sure.
Not the threedimensional photonic plane.
So expand the two dimensional concept of
the water waves into the
threedimensional realm. I get kind of
crazy. So let's talk about how the light
a single photon would act, right? We
shoot a photon out of the laser beam. Um
and it's going to hit the holographic
film first. This is a single beam
method. There's different ways to do
this. Um but it hits the film first,
hits the subject, right? the subject is
not going to be perfectly smooth. So,
it's going to scatter that photon. So,
we have like a cone of of light, right?
And the cone is going to come back into
the film. All right, that's the that's
the other wave. We got the wave shooting
in, we got the wave coming back out. And
now, inside of that holographic film
that's in between that wave pattern,
we're going to basically record our
interference pattern, our interference
point. So we do that about a billion
times across the entire surface of the
film because that's just how organic
capturing of film works. And now you
have a matrix of you know billions of
interference points that are all
reconstructing an image because of this
interference points uh during the
development process. Basically you have
metallic uh particles that are going to
align and become silvered so to speak or
refractive and that's how you get your
holographic light effect. uh because the
light is coming in, it's going to
reflect some back, but also focus it
like a lens do, right? And that's how we
get our shape.
So much like creating a a a sculpted toy
and making a cast of it and making a
mold, it's kind of like making a
holographic mold,
but you don't fill it with plastic or
resin. You fill it with light and then
it replays the original interference
pattern. It was recorded.
That's just my That's just off my dom
here. I There's a search engines.
Yeah, you know what I'm talking about.
You as you can read
you can read about it.